GABRIEL MALJKOVICH

Team Lead | Full Stack Developer E-mail:gabriel.l.maljkovich@gmail.com GitHub:@glmaljkovich

ABOUT ME

I'm a battle tested engineer. I worked in teams big and small with both feature-first and quality-first approaches and I frankly enjoyed them both. So I know how to handle myself in the midst of chaos and tight deadlines as well as when the focus is scalability and retrocompatibility.

I find my strong background in front-end development has helped me develop end-to-end features much faster than teammates who learn CSS on the go.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

Javascript, Python, Go, Java, Scala, Erlang, Elixir

FRONTEND FRAMEWORKS

Vue, React, Angular, React Native

BACKEND FRAMEWORKS

Node.js, Django, Flask, Feathers, Express, Laravel, Spark

INFRASTRUCTURE

Docker, Terraform, Kubernetes, AWS, Heroku

DATABASES

ClickHouse, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

EXPERIENCE

Lead Data Engineer

Nextroll, Inc.

November 2021 - Now

I spent the last 3 years building user deanonymization pipelines with Airflow and Apache Spark on AWS for the AdTech industry. I also built reporting dashboards for B2B ad campaigns in React, powered by Clickhouse, traversing 7Tb of data in milliseconds. And I didn't shy away from maintaining the Kubernetes cluster that hosted our ClickHouse DB.

Team Leader, FullStack Developer

Cambá Software Cooperative March 2016 - November 2021

Data Engineer for Adtech company (6 months)

Python, Java, Erlang, Presto, Spark, Hadoop, ClickHouse, AWS EMR/Batch/Lambda/SQS/DynamoDB

I became part of a data team handling the processing of 6 Billion records a day and building user and attributes profiles that would target Fortune 500 companies. Speed, scale, reliability and migrating a rapidly evolving codebase from Hadoop to Spark were the main concerns I worked on.

Full Stack Developer for Adtech company (6 months)

Python, React, Go, AWS Batch/Lambda/SQS, Flask, ClickHouse

We were spear-heading a new B2B platform which was the core product of the business unit. We focused on performance on and go-to-market speed. I migrated API's from python to Go and databases from Postgres to ClickHouse for faster reporting and analytics while maintaining a slick user interface in our React apps.

Cross-device targeting pipeline for Adtech company (6 months)

Python, Docker, Terraform, Postgres, Luigi, AWS Batch/Lambda/SQS, Flask

I was part of a team that had to develop a cross-device user targeting graph for an Ad company, processing 12 billion records a day, ingesting data from different identity providers to uniquely identify a user across all their devices and accounts.

CRM and ticketing platform for ground travel (1 year)

Vue, NodeJS, Mongo, AWS

As a Project Lead I managed a team of 4 developers working in the Site Reliability Engineering area. We audited and improved the apps and API's performance and security while modernizing the underlying frameworks (mongo, NodeJS, webpack and Vue). We also developed a core feature of the platform: Promos. Personally, I helped establish project structures and coding practices to reduce the technical debt across the codebase.

Reaction commerce site (1 year)

React | Meteor | Mongo | Docker

Worked as a Team Lead and Fullstack developer for an e-commerce PWA and developed features using React, Javascript, MongoDB and Docker while leading a team of 6 devs.

Management Platform for Callcenters (6 months)

Javascript, Semantic UI, Vue.js, Python, Django, MySQL

Freelance Web Designer

NEXTGEN DESIGN

2013 - 2016

I designed Websites, Newsletters and managed Online Marketing Campaigns.

EDUCATION

August 2014 – August 2019

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

National University of Quilmes - UNQ

January - March 2017

Friends of Fulbright Scholarship

University of Central Arkansas

I won a Fulbright Scholarship by the U.S. Embassy, where I took an intensive English Program and observed Computer Science classes.

August 2014 – August 2017

Bachelor's degree in Programming

National University of Quilmes – UNQ